PRASHANT MOHAN SINHA

Al Sharjah, UAE | +91-7781980618 / +971-526757837 sinha.pm@gmail.com

Summary



Hard-working professional with 16+ years of experience in the field of Geoscience with deep interest in Geocomputing, seeking an exciting and challenging position in a company where my skills and knowledge can be used to the fullest.

Experience

Vega Petroleum

Sr. Geophysicist | 09/2020 - Present

Asset: Offshore Exploration Blocks 2 & 17, Gulf of Suez, Egypt

- Carried out multi-survey multi-type offshore 3D seismic KPSTM, KPSDM & FWI reprocessing QC
- eFTG survey planning, processing & interpretation QC
- · Legacy seismic data structural interpretation with the integration of eFTG result
- Liaising with partner Zarubezneft, Moscow

RAK Gas LLC

Geophysicist | 12/2014 - 06/2020

Asset: Pemba-Zanzibar Block, Zanzibar, Tanzania

- Key contributor to the 2D seismic (Marine, Tz & Onshore) data acquisition planning, on-site field operation & data QC
- Carried out KPSTM processing QC with BGP, Kuala Lumpur & DUG, London
- eFTG survey planning, processing & interpretation QC
- Seismic data interpretation, Spectral Decomposition & Quantitative Analysis Frequency based AVO analysis with angle stacks, EEI

Asset: Ghazaliyat Onshore Block, Western Desert, Egypt

- 2D seismic (Marine, Tz & Onshore) data acquisition planning, field data QC
- Carried out KPSTM processing QC with PGS, Cairo
- Structural Interpretation, velocity analysis depth conversion of 2D seismic

Asset: Block 2 & 3, Lake Malawi, Malawi

- Structural interpretation of existing 2D seismic lines
- Post stack 2D vintage seismic data processing enhancement with Madagascar & Seismic Unix

Essar Exploration and Production Limited

Sr. Geophysicist | 10/2012 - 12/2014

Asset: OPL226 Offshore Block (Niger Delta), Nigeria

- 3D offshore seismic data acquisition planning, & data QC
- Carried out KPSTM processing QC with BGP, Port Harcourt
- Structural and Stratigraphic Interpretation, well-seismic tie, attribute analysis, on-off structure amplitude profiling, velocity modelling, depth conversion, volumetric estimation
- Co-ordinate with Regulator(s)

Essar Oil Ltd.

Exploration Geophysicist | 06/2005 - 10/2012

Asset: CB-ON/3 Onshore Block, Mehsana, India

Coordinated 3D seismic data acquisition (Alphageo)

Asset: Essar Raniganj Onshore Block, Durgapur, India

- 2D seismic data acquisition planning, on-site field operation & data QC
- Carried out KPSTM processing QC with Samit, India
- Cross-hole seismic survey: on-site field operation & data QC
- Conventional well logs acquisition and perforation: on-site field operation & data QC, lab desorption test
- Part of small team member to establish the field potential in first place

· Assisted in the Reserve Certification of asset by Netherland, Sewell & Associates Inc, USA

Skills

MATLAB (Signal Processing, Deep Learning), Python, C++, VB, BASH Shell, Petrel, IHS Kingdom, DUG Insight, QGIS

Education

Liverpool John Moores University, UK Master of Science in ML & AI | 06/2023 (Expected Graduation Date)

IIT(ISM) Dhanbad, India M.Sc. Tech Applied Geophysics | 05/2005

Ranchi University, India Mathematics Honours | 06/2001

GitHub / Articles

- I). 3D Seismic Data Phase Decomposition analysis by odd-even function
- II). Gravity-Magnetic: Directional Gray level transformed Normalized Standard Deviation for Edge/Lineament Detection
- III). Common contour stacking On-off structural amplitude profiling from 3D seismic point data set
- IV). Application of kriging and simulated annealing for spatial variability modelling of a coal seam

Awards

High Performance Award, Year 2018, RAK Gas LLC, UAE